# **LANE GARNER**

Austin, Texas b.lane.garner@gmail.com 913-484-8919

linkedin.com/in/LaneGarner github.com/LaneGarner LaneGarner.dev

#### **SUMMARY**

An enthusiastic and self-motivated web developer building custom websites and web applications using React, Node.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS/SCSS, Express, and MySQL. Experience with frontend, back-end, and full stack Agile development. I am a highly creative and driven musician and music educator continuing to expand my horizons. My experience with music taught me how to learn quickly and efficiently as I apply these skills to my love of coding and web development.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Software Developer**

Zollege

February 2021 - May 2021

- · Worked on a remote team to deploy two full-stack web applications for clients
- Implemented Agile Development methodologies along with technologies such as React, Node.js, Javascript, CSS/SCSS, HTML, MySQL, Bootstrap, and Figma to quickly deliver MVP
- Designed User Experience (UX) and User Interface (UI)
- Managed version control within a team environment using Git/GitHub branches and merges

# **Fullstack Developer**

**BLG** 

December 2019 - Present

- · Built websites for clients, secured seed funding, and onboarded three clients
- Engineered full stack applications with React, Node.js React Native, Firebase, Netlify, GraphQL, JavaScript, CSS, and HTML
- Worked actively with clients to ensure satisfaction and maintain QA

# Web Developer/Content Creator

GarnerGuitar.com

August 2002 - December 2020

- Created online guitar instruction content, courses, and advertising materials for lessons
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO) ranked number one on local Google search results for "guitar lessons" with 120% business growth in a year
- Iterated multiple versions of site utilizing React, Node.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and Wordpress

#### Music Professional

Lane Garner Music

August 2002 - Present

- Performed and recorded a variety of music while traveling across the country and world as a bandleader and supporting artist
- Taught guitar lessons up to the university level and built a successful business with satisfied clients

#### **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

#### Shedr.app

December 2020 - March 2021

- Musician's practice toolkit web application developed with React.js, Node.js, CSS/SCSS, Firebase Realtime Database (No SQL), Context API, Tone.js
- Integrated email, Google, Apple, & Facebook Authentication (user login authentication)
- Code: <a href="https://github.com/LaneGarner/shedr">https://github.com/LaneGarner/shedr</a> Hosted: <a href="https://shedr.app">https://shedr.app</a>

#### LaneGarner.dev

August 2020 - Present

- Personal portfolio site developed with React, Gatsby, SCSS, GraphQL, and Markdown
- Code: <a href="https://github.com/LaneGarner/new-portfolio">https://github.com/LaneGarner/new-portfolio</a> Hosted: <a href="https://lanegarner.dev">https://lanegarner.dev</a>

### **Today List App**

February 2021 - March 2021

- My version of the ultimate todo app developed with React Native, Firebase Firestore, Authentication, Redux
- Code: <a href="https://github.com/LaneGarner/today-list">https://github.com/LaneGarner/today-list</a> Hosted:

#### **SKILLS**

- React.js JavaScript (ES6+) Node.js npm HTML CSS SCSS/Sass JSON Express.js
- MySQL Redux Google Cloud Platform (GCP) Firebase Adobe suite Command line Git
- GitHub Bootstrap Material Visual Studio Code Trello Agile development Gatsby
- GraphQL

#### **EDUCATION**

**Austin Coding Academy**, Austin, TX Web Development Certification, JavaScript September 2020 - February 2021

University of North Texas, Denton, TX Master of Music, Jazz Studies/Guitar August 2010 - May 2013

**University of North Texas**, Denton, TX Bachelor of Music, Jazz Studies/Guitar *August 2006 - December 2010*